嘿, 你们好, 我是Cherno, 欢迎回到我的OpenGL系列教程
hey, what's up guys, my name is Cherno, welcome back to my OpenGL series
那么我们今天主要讲渲染器
so today we're gonna be talking all about the renderer
我们要写我们的第一个渲染器, 这是非常令人兴奋
and we're gonna be writing our first renderer, which is pretty exciting
到目前为止, 我们所有的都在主文件中
so far, all we have is in our main file
我们基本上只得到了一些类
we've basically just got a list of well classes
先创建, 然后绑定绘制等等
that get created, and then later get bound, and then get drawn and
只是有点乱
it's just a little kind of a mess
这些都不是通过中心管道的
and none of this is going through a central pipeline
这是我们这儿存在的大问题
which is really the big issue that we have here
对于我们像这样去实现一些东西还是挺不错的, 但是
it's still perfectly fine for us to do something like this, but
好吧, 而不是我们实际告诉别人
well, instead of us actually telling someone
嘿, 我有一些数据, 我想绘制个图
hey, I have some data, I would like a drawn
我们不得不做所有那些工作
we're having to do all of that work
因为一些原因, 那确实是一个问题, 首先
and that's a problem for a few reasons, first of all
它就是那样, 因为我们每次都在做所有的工作
it's that, because we're doing all the work every time
如果我们想再渲染一些东西
and if we want to render something again
我们不得不为那个创建一个绘制调用
well we have to make a draw call for that
我们不得不靠自己通过这种管道
and we have to go through that kind of pipeline all by ourselves
一次又一次
again and again and again
这很糟糕, 因为我们在重复代码
which is bad, because we're repeating code
它比较容易出错, 也比较烦人
it's error-prone, it's also just annoying
所有这些问题, 然后等到后面
all of those problems, and then later
当这些变得更复杂的时候
when things get more complicated
我们有多个渲染目标
and we have multiple rendering targets
或者甚至是像混合一样简单的一些东西
or even something simple like blending
我们没有一种中心粘合剂把一切联系在一起
we have no kind of central glue that ties everything together
实际让一切保持有组织, 可调试, 运行顺利
and actually keeps everything organized and debuggable and running smoothly
那就是渲染器的作用
and that's kind of where the renderer comes in
渲染器就像工厂, 这里我们说的是一些部件
the renderer is like the factory, where we say here are some parts
我想让你给我创建个东西
I want you to make something for me
这是我即兴编出来的
I literally made that up on a spot
但你知道吗, 我觉得这很有效
but you know what, I guess it works
所以我们要坚持那个
so we're going to stick with that
所以基本上这里的想法很简单
so basically the idea here is fairly simple
我们有一堆数据, 就比如下面这些形式的
we have a bunch of data in the form of like
顶点缓冲区, 索引缓冲区和着色器等等
a vertex buffer and index buffer, a shader, whatever
我们希望能够把它给别人, 然后说
and we want to be able to give that to someone and say
嘿, 我给你的这个东西
hey, this stuff that I'm giving you
我需要显示在屏幕上
I want to appear in the screen please
那就是渲染器的职责, 现在
and that's kind of what the job of a renderer is, now
当然, 它比那个要复杂的多
of course it gets a lot more complicated than that
我们可以告诉渲染器许多东西
and we can tell the renderer a lot of things
但为了简单起见, 我们今天的目标就是移除
but to keep it simple, our goal for today is really just to move away
我们实际在我们主文件中上次遗留的OpenGL调用
the last remaining OpenGL call that we actually have inside our main file
当我们看看我们的代码
if we take a look at our code
你可以看到所有这些中相当多的已经被抽象出去了
you can see that pretty much all of this is abstracted away
我的意思是, 我们已经有了, 像VertexArray和VertexBuffer
I mean we have like VertexArray VertexBuffer
我们已经得到了IndexBuffer和Shader所有这些类
we've got IndexBuffer, we've got Shader, we've got all of this stuff
那完全被抽象到我们的自定义类中了
that is just completely abstracted away into our custom classes
然而, 我猜我们有两个OpenGL调用
however well, I guess we have two OpenGL calls
我们已经得到了应该被渲染器处理的glClear
we've got the glClear which should be handled by the renderer
然后我们也有这个DrawElements, 所以这个基本上就是个绘制
and then we've also got this DrawElements, so this is basically a draw
这个就是叫DrawCall的东西, 正如我们之前讨论的
this is something called a DrawCall, as we've discussed previously
这是我们实际告诉OpenGL的地方, 我想让你取绑定的任何东西
it's where we actually tell OpenGL, I want you to take whatever's bound
然后把这个绘制在屏幕上, 这就是glDrawElements所做的
and just draw this on the screen somehow, and that's what glDrawElements does
这应该由渲染器来处理
that should be something that is taken care of by the renderer
因为那很清楚, 但很清楚的是
as is that clear thing, but the clear thing is
这是我们以后可能会讲到的一个小问题
kind of a minor thing which we'll probably get into later
不论如何, 我们如何实现那个, 好吧
anyway how are we going to do that well
我们要从创建一个Renderer类开始
we're going to start by making a Renderer class
然后在那个Renderer类中, 我们会写一个Draw方法
and then inside that Renderer class, we're going to be writing a Draw function
基本上就是接收一大堆参数, 那么
which basically takes in a bunch of arguments, so
这些数据, 那个实际需要绘制一些东西
the data that actually needs to draw something
然后用那种方法绘制在屏幕上
and then draws it on the screen and from that approach
即使那可能看起来确实比较简单
even though that might seem like a really simple thing
我们可以把它扩展成非常复杂和非常强大的东西
we can grow that into into something extremely complex and extremely powerful
那么让我们直接进入代码并检查一下
so let's get right into the code and check that out
所以我首先要做的就是, 右键点击这个src, 点击添加新项
so the first thing I'm going to do is, right click on src here, hit add new item
创建一个叫Renderer.h的头文件
gonna make a header file called Renderer.h
显然我已经得到了Renderer.h, 以及Renderer.cpp
and apparently I've already got the Renderer.h, and Renderer.cpp
那就是我们放我们所有OpenGL东西的地方, 所以那很好
yep that's where we put all of our OpenGL stuff, so that's great
那么在我们的Renderer.h文件中, 我要给这里腾点空间
so inside our Renderer.h, I'm just gonna make some room here and
实际上创建一个叫Renderer的类
actually make a class called Renderer
现在, 这个类是否应该是静态的
now whether this class should be static
或者它应该是一个单例之类的
or it should be a singleton or anything like that
那是值得商榷的
that's it's up for debate
我的意思是, 有些人喜欢把这个类变成单例
I mean some people like to actually make this class a singleton
确保只有一个这样的单例
and make sure there's only a single instance of that
有些人不喜欢那样做
some people don't like to do that
因为他们可能想要Renderer的多个实例
because maybe they might want to have multiple instances of the Renderer
这很完美, 对吧, 这两种方法都不是错的
that's perfectly, okay, it's not neither approaches really wrong
它只是取决于你需要如何去使用它
it's just how you want to do it
我们只会让这个变得不那么
we're just gonna make this not kind
我不会让这里的每个方法都是静态的, 或者之类的任何处理
I'm not gonna make every method here static or anything like that
我们会把它当作可以有多个实例
we're just gonna treated as if we can have multiple instances of this
如果我们选择那样做, 也许就是一些处理
if we choose to that, might be something
如果你有多个图层, 你可能会想这么做
you might want to do if you have multiple layers
或者在你实际的图形应用中有类似的东西
or something like that inside your actual graphics application
但我们没有理由做得太过火
but there's no reason for us to kind of go overboard
然后开始创建一切, 从这里开始
and just start making everything, started here
那么我就把它当做一个普通类来对待
so I'm just going to treat this as if it was a normal class
我们的第一个目标是创建一个叫做Draw的方法, 它会接收一些参数
so our first goal is really just to make a function called Draw, which takes in a bunch of stuff
所以让我们想想, 在OpenGL绘制一些东西, 我们实际需要什么
so let's think about what we actually need to draw something in OpenGL
唔, 我们需要顶点数组和索引缓冲区
well, we need a vertex array, we need an index buffer
以及着色器, 那就是我们目前所知道的, 对吧
and we need a shader, that's what we know so far, right
这个顶点数组实际已经绑定了顶点缓冲区的
the vertex array actually has the vertex buffer bound to it
所以我们一点儿也不担心顶点缓冲区
so we don't need to worry about vertex buffers at all
但我们确实需要那个索引缓冲区, 当然还有我之前提到的顶点数组
but we do need to have that index buffer, the vertex array of course as I mentioned
以及一个有效的着色器, 所以这三个东西就是我们所需要的
and also a valid shader, so those three things are really all we need
现在索引缓冲区有这个索引计数
now the index buffer has the index count
如果我们传入一个索引缓冲区到这个Draw方法
and if we kind of pass in an index buffer into this Draw function
我们可以假设我们想要绘制整个索引缓冲区
we can kind of assume that we want to draw that entire index buffer
因为如果我们想绘制一部分索引缓冲区
because if we wanted to draw like a partial index buffer
我们可能传入一个索引缓冲区, 它只有一部分索引
we probably pass in an index buffer, which just had a partial set of indices
那么在Draw这儿, 我就写VertexArray&
so over here in Draw, I'm going to write VertexArray&
我将通过引用传递这些, 通过常量引用
I'm going to pass all these by reference, by constant reference
那么就是const VertexArray& va, const IndexBuffer& ib
so VertexArray va, const IndexBuffer ib
然后是const Shader& shader, 酷
and then const Shader& shader, cool
那么继续, 我们也会把那个创建成静态的
so there we go, and we can make that constant as well
因为我们不会改变任何东西
since we won't be modifying anything
在Renderer头文件中
into the Renderer
我会在这包含所有类, 就是VertexArray, IndexBuffer和Shader
I'm going to include all of our classes here, VertexArray IndexBuffer and Shader
那在我看来很不错
and that's looking pretty good to me
所以在Renderer.cpp中
so in Renderer.cpp
我会写那个方法, 所以就是void Renderer::Drawer()
I'm going to write that function, so void Renderer::Drawer
我只想保留这一切，同时也要标记那个为静态的
I'm just gonna let it sit all that for me, remark that as const as well
现在我们可以把DrawCall移动到这里
and now we can actually move our DrawCall here
那么让我们返回Application文件, 看看我们实际需要移动的是什么
so let's go back to Application, and see what it is we actually need to move
那么我们已经绑定了顶点数组和索引数组以及这个着色器
so we had this vertex array binding, this index array binding and this shader binding
现在有趣的是, 我们实际设置了一个统一变量
now what's interesting here is we're actually setting a uniform
那么这如何与我们的Draw函数一起工作
so how is that going to work with our Draw function
我们待会再讲这个
well we'll come back to that later
但暂时就让我们复制所有这些代码
but for now let's just grab all of this code
进入Renderer.cpp, 然后关闭其他这些文件
I'm going to go into Renderer.cpp, and we just close these other files
像那样粘贴在这里, 不用担心这个设置统一变量
gonna paste that in here like that, don't worry about the set uniform
那么我们已经绑定了着色器, 顶点数组和索引缓冲区
so we have our shader binding, our vertex array binding and our index buffer binding
然后返回Application文件
and then finally back in Application
我们也像那样复制glDrawElements
we'll steal that glDrawElements just like that
那么我们就调用GLCall(glDrawElements(GL_TRIANGLES))
and so we'll do GLCall glDrawElements triangles
现在为了代替6, 我们可以使用ib.GetCount()
now instead of 6, we're going to have index buffer GetCount
我想我们假设过unsigned int, 这总是一个unsigned int
unsigned int I think we assumed that, this is always going to be an unsigned int
正如你在这里看到的数据
as you can see here with the data
那么我们基本上会隐藏代码, 这就是unsigned int
so we will just basically hide code, this to be unsigned int
但在这种情况下, 你可能有unsigned short作为你的索引类型
but in the case of, you may be having unsigned short as your index type
你可能想把它从索引缓冲区中取出, 或者任何你存储它的地方
you might want to actually pull that out of the index buffer, or wherever you're storing that
最后我们暂时把所有东西都画成三角形
and then finally we're drawing everything as triangles for now
我们肯定会在将来进入不同的渲染模式
we will definitely get into kind of different modes of rendering in the future
但目前, 它只是三角形, 因为这就是我们要做的
but for now, it's just going to be triangles, because that's what we're doing
好了, 酷, 一切看起来都很好, 在我们的代码中
okay, cool, so everything looks pretty good, in our code
你可以看到那个编译也不错
you can see that compiles just fine
我们不打算解绑这些东西
we're not going to bother unbinding any of this
在更传统的情况下, 比如解绑这个概念
in a more tradition, like this whole concept of unbinding
我真的应该为此专门做一期视频, 但就像
I really should make a video dedicated about that about this, but like
在OpenGL中解绑不是严格必要的, 如果它对调试有用的话
unbinding stuff in OpenGL not strictly necessary, if it is useful for debugging
我会那么说, 但是它可能会减少一些bug
I will say that, but and it might reduce some bugs maybe
但从根本上来说
but ultimately speaking
在OpenGL中解绑东西只是浪费性能, 你不需要这么做
unbinding stuff in OpenGL is just a waste of performance, you don't really need to do that
因为在我们绘制下一个东西之前, 我们会把这些东西都绑定起来
because before we draw the next thing, we'll be binding all this stuff anyway
所以解绑没有意义
so there's no real point
更复杂的系统可能在调试模式下会有解绑
more kind of complex systems might have like unbinding in debug mode and then
在发布模式下, 解绑当然什么都不做
in release mode the unbind courses do nothing
这是一种选项, 我们可能会实现类似的东西
that's one option, and we might implement something like that
当我们真的在制作游戏引擎的时候
if we were actually making a game engine
但暂时我们要这样写代码, 那已经不错了
but for now we're just gonna write our code like this, and that would be fine
你可能会说, 把解绑代码放在这里会更明智
you could probably argue that it would be wiser for me to actually put unbinding code here
因为, 再说一次, 我们这里严格来说讲的是OpenGL
because again, we are strictly kind of talking about OpenGL here
我们并没有真正开发一个游戏引擎
we're not really writing a game engine
所以我们可能不关心性能之类的东西
so we probably don't really care about performance or anything like that
我确实喜欢保持代码的整洁
I do like to keep my code kind of clean though
只需要再多三行代码来解绑定所有这些不必要的东西
and just having three more lines to unbind all of this stuff needlessly
就像我只是不想把代码弄得太乱
like I just don't want to clutter the code too much
这就是为什么我在这里不这么做的原因, 好吧
so that's the reason why I'm not doing that here, okay
那么返回Application文件, 我们仍然有这个统一变量的问题
so back in Application, we still have this uniform issue
没有什么能阻止我们这么做
there's nothing really stopping us from just doing this
就像我们仍然可以这样做, 然后我们不需要绑定任何东西
like we can still do this, and then we don't need to bind any of that
然后对于这个Renderer
and then finally for the Renderer
我在这里要做的就是创建这个Renderer类的一个新实例
what I'm going to do here is just create a new instance of this Renderer class
就像这样Renderer renderer
just like this Renderer renderer
然后在这里, 我们将调用renderer.Draw()
and then over here, we're just going to call renderer.Draw
传入我们的顶点数组
we're going to pass in our vertex array
索引缓冲区和着色器
we're going to pass in our index buffer and we're going to pass in our shader
就像那样
just like that
那么我们基本上告诉我们的渲染器
and so we're basically telling our renderer here
嘿, 我现在有个顶点数组, 索引缓冲区和着色器
hey, I have a vertex array, an index buffer and a shader
把那个绘制到屏幕上去
please draw that onto the screen
那就是我们方法的功能
and that's kind of what our function does
那么如果我们到这里, 运行这个应用程序
so if we come over here, and we actually run this application of ours
我们会得到一大堆错误, 因为有些东西没有找到
we're going to get a whole bunch of errors here, because something's not found
这可能是因为我们实际上在这里包含了Renderer
it's probably because we're actually including Renderer in here
然后它也会被包含到Renderer中
and then that's being included into Renderer as well
所以我们这儿得到了一个循环的包含过程
so we kind of got a cyclical include thing going on here
那么让我们直接去看看那个
so let's go ahead and check that
VertexArray,VertexBufferLayout, 因为我们需要那个
VertexArray VertexBufferLayout, because we do need that
那是一个引用, 所以我们可以排除它
that is a reference though, so we could eliminate that
让我们看看VertexBufferLayout, 就是这个原因
let's see if I think VertexBufferLayout, yeah, the reason
这是因为在VertexBufferLayout中调用了ASSERT
this happens is because VertexBufferLayout calls ASSERT
我认为这是唯一的原因, 我们在这儿需要Renderer
I think that's the only reason, we need Renderer here
事实上，我们还包含一个OpenGL
isn't it, well, actually we also include a OpenGL
好了, 当然, 为了解决这个问题, 我们会去到VertexArray.h文件
okay, sure, so to kind of solve this what we'll do is, we will actually go to VertexArray.h
我不打算在这里包含VertexBufferLayout
I'm not going to include VertexBufferLayout in here
我要在声明之前, 输入像这样的class VertexBufferLayout
I'm actually going to before declare, by just typing in class VertexBufferLayout like that
然后在cpp文件中, 我会像那样包含VertexBufferLayout
and then in the cpp file, I'm going to include VertexBufferLayout just like that
这样我们就不会在这里包含VertexBufferLayout
so that way we don't actually include VertexBufferLayout in here
问题就是VertexBufferLayout包含了Renderer
the problem really is the VertexBufferLayout includes Renderer
我们在Renderer.h中包含VertexArray, 它包含了VertexBufferLayout
and then we include VertexArray which includes VertexBufferLayout inside Renderer.h
所以它就像在VertexArray中包含Renderer
so it's like we're including Renderer in VertexArray
我们也在Renderer包含了VertexArray
and we're including VertexArray in Renderer
它有点像, 它进入了一个无限循环的包含
and it's kind of, it's getting into like an infinite loop of inclusion
我会有一个C++视频, 在某种程度上是关于生存周期的
well I'll have a c++ video about that available at some point in my life
如果有的话, 就点击那里
click there, if it's there
所以如果我们尝试再次编译我们的代码
so if we try and compile our code once again
应该会成功的, 好吧
we should be okay, alright
那么回到Application.cpp, 我们还必须包含那个VertexBufferLayout
so back in Application.cpp, we also have to include that VertexBufferLayout
所以我会像那样包含那个
so I'll include that like that
然后编译我们的代码, 好了, 成功了
and compile our code, all right, there we go, success
让我们直接去运行一下这个应用
let's go ahead and launch this application
看看我们能否得到同样的渲染东西
and see if we get the same thing rendering
你可以看到我们得到了相同的结果
and you can see that we have the same result
太好了, 为了清理这里, 我们还要做几件事
great, few more things that we can actually do, to clean this up is
我们这里有这个glClear
we have this glClear here
当然, 这里我真的不想那么做
I don't really want to do that here of course
那么在Renderer.h中, 我就写Clear
so inside Renderer.h, I'm just going to write Clear
然后在cpp文件中, 我要实现这个方法Clear
and then inside the cpp file, I'm going to implement that function Clear
我们基本上就会复制粘贴我们在Application中的东西
and we'll just basically copy and paste what we have inside Application
这是颜色缓冲, 就像这样
which is color buffer a bit, just like that
我们只需要像那样调用Renderer.Clear()
and we'll just call Renderer.Clear like that
为了更准确一点
and to be a little bit more correct
我要做的就是把这个方法标记为const, 当然它什么都没做
what I'm going to do is mark this function as const, of course it doesn't do anything
只在这种情况下, 我们有约束条件或类似的东西
just in case, we have a constraint or anything like that
回到Application文件, 看看我们做了什么
and if we go back to Application, let's just see what we've done
所以本质上, 我们所做的是我们去掉了每一个GLCall
so essentially what we've done is we've gotten rid of every single GLCall
我想在整个文件都有
I think that we have in this entire file yep
我们所做的就是整个渲染过程
and so what we've done is that whole rendering situation that we've had
我们基本上改变了
we've basically changed
我们已经创建了一些绘制函数
we've made some kind of drawing functions
这样我们就可以用适当的数据调用Draw方法
so that we can just call Draw with the appropriate data
然后清除, 如果我们实际想清屏
and then clear, if we actually want to clear our screen
我们使用着色器时仍然有这种问题
we do still have this kind of issue here with the shader
我们实际还需要在哪儿绑定着色器
where we actually still have to kind of bind the shader
这样我们就可以在每一帧中任意设置统一变量
so that we can set the uniform to whatever we want every frame
我不喜欢把代码留在这里
I'm not a big fan of leaving that code in here
解决这个问题的唯一方法是
the only real way to solve that though is
因为我们喜欢你们解决这个问题的方法是使用材质而不是着色器
because we like the way that you would solve that is by using materials instead of shaders
那么我们的Draw方法中有什么, 也就是Renderer.Draw
so what we have in our Draw function, and Renderer.Draw
我们会接收顶点数组, 索引缓冲区和着色器
we're taking in a vertex array an index buffer and a shader
这在更传统的设置中有点奇怪, 我们会接收, 就像
that's a bit weird in a more traditional setup, we'd be taking in like
你知道的, 顶点数组, 任何索引缓冲区, 都可以
you know, vertex array, whatever index buffer, that's all fine
但然后我们就会使用一个材质代替一个真正的着色器
but then we'd be taking in a material instead of an actual shader
材质基本上就是一个着色器加上一套
and what a material is is basically a shader plus a set of diner
所以就是一个着色器加上它所有的统一变量
so a shader plus all of its uniforms
不管那是渲染器的一种特殊的统一变量
whether that be kind of renderer specific uniforms
或者是每个对象的统一变量, 例如, 这个矩形的颜色
or kind of per object uniforms, like, for example, this rectangle's color
就像我们实际拥有的一种每个对象的统一变量
would be like a kind of per object uniform that we actually have
那将被存储在材质中, 就在着色器的旁边
and that would be stored inside the material, alongside the shader
这样, 当我们把材质传递给渲染器的时候
and so that way, when we pass in the material to the renderer
渲染器基本上会绑定材质
the renderer will basically bind the material
这意味着它会绑定着色器, 设置它所需的所有统一变量
meaning that it would bind the shader,and set up all the uniforms that it needs to
然后在我们索引周围调用顶点数组的Draw方法
and then call the Draw function for our vertex array around our index
但是对于那些东西
but for and all that kind of stuff
那么那就是它的运行原理
so that's how it should work
我们没有材质, 是的, 或者类似的东西
we don't have materials, yeah, or anything like that
所以目前, 实际上, 我们必须, 如果我们想修改一个着色器的统一变量
so for now, we have to actually, if we want to modify a uniform for a shader
我们必须自己手动完成, 这有点烦人
we have to do that ourselves manually, a little bit annoying
我们将来可能会接触到材质
we might get into materials in the future
在游戏引擎系列教程中我们肯定会碰到的
we definitely will in the game engine series
不确定OpenGL系列, 但我们可能不得不这样做
not sure about OpenGL series, we probably will have to though
这很快就会变得很复杂
this is gonna get pretty complicated pretty soon
所以对于你们这些认为这是变得
so for all of you people who are thinking this is getting
到目前为止有点简单
there's a bit simple so far
反正很快就会升级的
it's gonna escalate pretty quickly anyway
Renderer类的方法相当多的
that's pretty much the Renderer
我们现在有一个可以持续添加的类了
we now have a class that we can keep adding to
当我们实际需要渲染越来越多的东西
when we actually need to render more and more things
我迫不及待地想进入更复杂的东西
I can't wait to get into the more complicated stuff
接下来我们将讨论纹理
next up we're going to talk about textures
以及我们如何在OpenGL中渲染纹理和低级纹理以及所有这些东西
and how we can render textures and low textures and do all of that stuff in OpenGL
在那之后, 我想我们可能会转向其他东西, 比如3D模型
and after that, I think we're probably going to move on to things, like 3D models
或者我不知道有那么多事情要做
or I don't know there's so much so much to do
我认为3D模型可能是个好主意
I think 3D models is probably a good idea
我们可能还需要讲一些调试接口
we probably want to move on to some kind of debugging interface as well
就像一个图形用户界面系统, 这样我们就可以使用它了
and like a GUI system, so that we can play around with that
一旦我们有了3D模型, 我们可以转移到光源和像那样更酷的东西
once we have 3D models, we can move on to lighting and cool stuff like that
在某些时候, 我们还是需要进行文本渲染
we also need to do text rendering at some point
只会是一场噩梦, 当然我讨厌做文本渲染
just gonna be a nightmare, of course I hate doing a text rendering
我可能会写一个库
I might actually write a library
特别是为了使本系列的文本渲染更容易
specifically to make text rendering easier for this series
因为这真的很烦人
because it's really quite annoying
我真的不想处理那个, 但另一方面
and I don't really want to deal with that, but then on the other hand
我需要向你们展示实际文本渲染的原理
I need to show you guys how to actually make text rendering work
在不使用库的情况下, 所以那还是比较有趣
without using libraries, so that's gonna be fun
不论如何, 希望你们喜欢这个视频
anyway I hope you guys enjoyed this video
如果你们喜欢的话, 就可以点击那个喜欢按钮
if you did, you can hit that like button
你们也可以通过parteon.com/TheCherno来支持这个系列教程
you can also help support this series by going to parteon.com/TheCherno
非常感谢所有支持我在YouTube上制作视频的人
huge thank you as always to all of the supporters of all of the videos that I make here on YouTube
因为没有那些优秀的人, 它们就不会存在
because they wouldn't be here, without those wonderful people
下次就是纹理, 再见
next time textures, I will see you next time
下次, 下次, 我会经常提到这个词, 拜
next time, next time, I'll just say that word a bit more often, goodbye